# Jean Carlos Medina

Kissimmee, Florida 34741

Phone: (786) 426-5577 | Email: datajcmg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jcmg">https://www.github.com/JCMedinaG</a>

Portfolio: https://jcmedinag.github.io/Portfolio

#### **Professional Summary**

Data Analyst with more than 10 years of professional experience, and a strong knowledge of statistical methods, data gathering and analysis. Awarded with a certification in Data Analytics and Visualization Bootcamp at UCF. Comfortable with tools like Excel, Python, SQL, R, and Tableau. Proven technical and leadership abilities in data warehousing, data healthcare, and data management environments. Passionate about data analytics and learning new technologies.

#### **Technical Skills:**

Programming and Software: Python, R, Excel, JavaScript, Pandas, Matplotlib, Plotly, Tableau, Power Bi, Microsoft Project, Visio, Office,

Surfer.

**Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB. **Version Control:** GitHub, Git.

Data Skills: Mining, Processing, Cleaning, Modeling, Visualization, ETL.

Other Skills: Preventive Maintenance. Logistics, Safety and Health, and Operations Management.

### **Projects:**

- Plotly.js-Project: This is an interactive dashboard to explore the Belly Button Biodiversity Dataset, a project created using JavaScript and Plotly, and hosted on Heroku which it is very helpful to deploy projects. https://resi360.herokuapp.com/
- Leaflet.js-Project: A visualization dashboard showing all earthquakes from the past 7 days. The project was created using JavaScript, Leaflet.js, and hosted on GitHub. https://jcmedinag.github.io/Leaflet.js-Project
- HTML-Project: A website using HTML and CSS where we can visualize weather data, these pages will contain the visualizations and their corresponding explanations. https://jcmedinag.github.io/Web-Project/

# **Experience**

#### Lincoln Property Company • Orlando, FL.

Building Engineer 2017–Present

Accomplishments:

✓ Took part in designing a preventive maintenance plan for identification of needed repairs or actions required to prevent damage to equipment and structures using analytics tools like Tableau and Excel.

### Diamond Resorts International - Orlando, FL.

Engineering Technician 2015–2017

Accomplishments:

✓ Made significant contribution in improving safety levels of the workplace, particularly in relation to chemicals and several dangerous goods using databases, and Excel to analyze improvement over the years.

# Maracaibo Polyclinic • Maracaibo, Venezuela

Safety and Health Engineer 2013-2015

Accomplishments:

✓ Succeeded in formulating a contingency plan to address emergency cases at the clinic using Microsoft Project, Excel and Visio.

# **Education**

Data Analytics and Visualization Boot Camp: 2019
University of Central Florida • Orlando, Florida
Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering: 2013
RAFAEL URDANETA UNIVERSITY • Maracaibo, Venezuela